Welcome! In this video, we'll break down the K-Means algorithm,
a popular method for clustering data. Let's start by understanding
the overall idea of grouping similar data points together.
The first step in K-Means is initialization, where we select K
random points to serve as the initial centroids for our clusters.
Next, every data point is assigned to the
nearest centroid based on distance, effectively forming initial
clusters. This is known as the assignment step.
After assigning points, we compute new centroids by taking the
mean of all points within each cluster. This update step
moves the centroids to the center of their clusters.
The algorithm iterates through the assignment and
update steps until the centroids no longer
change significantly, indicating convergence and well-defined clusters.